Hari Om Vatsal.
Happy Janmashtami.
On the sacred occasion of Lord Kṛṣṇa's birthday, let's open our heart and immerse ourselves in the divine Leela of Lord Kṛṣṇa.
And 1 by 1, he killed 6 of their children.
The seventh child was about to be born.
Incarnation of Sheshna, a cosmic serpent with thousand of fruits.
At this time, Lord Viṣṇu instructed Yogmaya, the Devi of cosmic illusion, to descend on earth and transfer Balram from Devaki's womb to Rohini's womb.
Now let's get into the mystic meaning behind Kṛṣṇa's birth story.
that we should not think about these stories that it happened in a particular Yoga, in a particular setting and we distance ourselves from these stories.
But when that aspiration dawns in the aspirant's heart, the celestial voice is heard and it sends challenge to the ego that is overpowered by ignorance.
He killed all the 6 children.
first and foremost, Kṛṣṇa's birth represents the birth of spiritual aspiration deep within the heart of a sincere aspirant.
And this has been beautifully explained by our Pujya Gurudev, Swami Jyotirmayanandaji, in the form of integral Yoga, which in a simple term is be good, do good, love, serve, meditate, and ultimately realize our absolute self, our real potential.
Let us make ourselves deserving so that we can joyously celebrate festival of Janmashtami every day within our own heart.
Hari Om Tat Sat Happy Janmashtami.